#### Contact

780-966-2257 (Mobile) churchmf@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/churchmf (LinkedIn)

matthewchurch.ca (Personal)

### Top Skills

Game Development

C#

Virtual Reality (VR)

### Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) French (Limited Working)

#### Certifications

Introduction to User Experience Design

Software Product Management Specialization

Virtual Reality Overview for Developers

Docker Technologies for DevOps and Developers

#### **Publications**

A Demonstration of ScriptEase II

Presentation: Improving Content Creator Workflow and Ensuring Quality with Big Data and Video

Presentation: Enhancing Telemetry Context With Video

ScriptEase II: Platform Independent Story Creation Using High-Level Patterns

Presentation: Improving Workflow and Ensuring Quality with Big Data and Video

#### **Patents**

Synchronized Video with In Game Telemetry

# Matthew Church

Programmer and Game Developer Edmonton

### Summary

Experienced, passionate, and accredited Software Developer with a focus on games, user-experience, virtual reality, web, automation and tools development. Credited on multiple video games ranging from AAA sport titles to epic role playing narrative adventures. Versed in game design and computer graphics. Tools developer with knowledge in database integration, data processing, user interface design, software testing and quality analysis.

Shipped titles:

FIFA 13

FIFA 14

FIFA World Cup 2014,

Dragon Age Inquisition,

Mass Effect Andromeda,

Anthem

# Experience

Improbable
Automation Tools Programmer
May 2020 - Present (11 months)
Edmonton, Alberta, Canada

Developing tailored tools solutions and automated workflows for various disciplines across the team including art, design, localization and programming. Creating, owning, and optimizing studio wide continuous integration and build pipelines to ensure game quality and improve iteration. Integrating changes and extending Unreal 4 to suit our needs. Documenting and educating teams about perforce strategies and tooling to enable others to work at their best.

Serious Labs Inc.
Senior Programmer
June 2018 - May 2020 (2 years)
Edmonton, Canada Area

Collaborated with art, design, production, and quality assurance to create virtual reality training simulators in Unity. Met with stakeholders across the team to improve workflow and develop tooling to facilitate content creation and project scalability. Programmed player movement models, fixed project wide bugs, and ran seminars teaching best practices. Developed automated testing systems and preflight tooling to ensure software quality and reduce build breakages.

Bioware Software Developer June 2014 - June 2018 (4 years 1 month) Edmonton, Canada Area

Designed and implemented company wide internal web applications in an agile team. Expanded scalable and intuitive tools utilized by dozens of game teams and occupations including programmers, designers, testers, and managers. Improved existing workflows by integrating web applications with game engine and development tools. Experience leading small development team in agile planning and delivering software on time and quality. Lead design meetings and meet with users to improve existing systems.

Electronic Arts (EA)
Software Engineer
July 2013 - June 2014 (1 year)
Vancouver, Canada Area

Software Engineer on the FIFA Games Mode Team. Working extensively with producers, quality assurance and other engineers to deliver high quality features for the game. Participated in agile sprint planning in a large team in order to meet deliverables on a deadline. Tested, wrote and debugged C++ and ActionScript.

Electronic Arts (EA)
Associate Software Engineer
January 2012 - September 2012 (9 months)
Burnaby, Canada

Associate Software Engineer on the FIFA Games Mode Team. Worked extensively with producers, quality assurance and other engineers to deliver high quality features for the game. Took ownership of several features both

new and old. Tested, wrote and debugged C++ and SQL.

University of Alberta Software Developer Intern May 2010 - September 2011 (1 year 5 months) Edmonton, Canada Area

ScriptEase Research Project. Developed and implemented extendible tools in a team environment which allow users to script video games without any programming experience. Attended weekly meetings emphasizing scrum planning, feature development and brainstorming. The code base grew to just over 12,000 lines during my time on the project.

## Education

University of Alberta

BSc, Computing Science Specialization · (2007 - 2013)